Guide to the Autograph Manuscript collection ARC.206
Brooklyn Historical Society
Autograph Manuscript collection
1700-1945
Brooklyn Historical Society
ARC.206
1.5 Linear Feet in two manuscript boxes and one oversize flatbox.
The collection consists of 1.5 linear feet of autographs isolated and within letters by or from notable historical figures not necessarily limited to Brooklyn, but who have some connection to Brooklyn, Long Island, New York, or Brooklynites.
Arrangement
Autographs are alphabetically foldered by surname.
Scope and Contents
This is an assembled collection of autographs isolated and within letters by or from notable historical figures who have some connection to Brooklyn, Long Island, New York, or Brooklynites.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This is an assembled collection comprised of the following accessions: 1974.011, 1974.076 (donated by C.L. Lee), 1974.010, 1974.009, and 1974.001, 1974.054.
Adams, John; Arnold, Benedict; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor); Brown, John; Burr, Aaron; Calhoun, John Caldwell; Clinton, DeWitt; Fulton, Robert; Greene, Nathanael; Irving, Washington; Jefferson, Thomas; L'Hommedieu, Ezra; Lee, Charles; Lincoln, Abraham; Prud'Homme, John Francis Eugene; Washington, George; Woodhull, Nathaniel
- Adams, John, 1777; 1974.001 folder 1; 4587; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  1777 wartime letter re: troop levies
- Adams, John, 1815, nd; 1974.009 folder 1; 4596; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  ND note, from former President John Adams, at Quincy, to "Sir," re: excusing "J. and C. Adams" from school on account of the weather; 1815 letter, from former President John Adams, at Quincy, MA, to Rev. Dr. Morse, re: Unitarianism, [copy?], with photocopy.
- Andre, John, 1778; 1974.054; 4597; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Arnold, Benedict, 1754, 1772, 1775, 1780; 1974.001 folder 2; 4588; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 4, Box OS-35)
  1754 letter from Hannah Arnold, at Norwich, to her son Benedict, at Canterbury, with parental advice; 1775 letter from Adj. General Horatio Gates to Colonel Benedict Arnold, at Watertown, re: Arnold's departure from Cambridge and his 'plan', mentions General Schuyler and General George Washington; 1780 letter from Benedict Arnold, at "Head Quarters Robinsons House," addressed to "Madam", re: food stores and the need for a house maid, mentions Mrs. Arnold.
- Balmanno, Robert, 1856; 1974.009 folder 2; 4589; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
  1856 letter, from Robert Balmanno, at New York, to Gabriel Harrison, daguerreotypist [of Brooklyn], re: portrait of Shakespeare for Mary Cowden Clarke, with extracts from an 1856 letter by Clarke.
- Bancroft, George, 1842; 1974.009 folder 3; 4598; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
  1842 letter, from George Bancroft, at Boston, to John L. O'Sullivan, at New York, re: O'Sullivan's proposed biography of Andrew Jackson, Bancroft's proposed history of the American Revolution, and the matter of establishing international copyright, mentions Amos Kendall, and Charles Dickens [See also: letters of George Bancroft in "Henry Onderdonk Jr. (1804-1886) Correspondence, 1835-18—", Box A0028, folder "Bancroft, George"]
- Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor), 1851; 1974.001 folder 3; 4599; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 7)
  1851 Concert ticket, signed by P. T. Barnum, "M'lle Jenny Lind's First Grand Concert, Wednesday, May 7th [1851]", issued to J. Madison Huntting
- Beers, Seth P., 1827; 1974.009 folder 5; 4600; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
  1827 letter, from Seth P. Beers, at Litchfield, to Victory Birdseye, re: funds, mentions Amos Lyman
- Bokee, David Alexander, 1848; 1974.009 folder 6; 4601; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 9)
  1848 letter, from David Alexander Bokee, at Albany, to Alden J. Spooner, Joshua M. Van Cott, and W. Wallace, as committee members of the Hamilton Literary Association, Brooklyn, re: the committee's invitation
- Bonaparte, Napoleon, 1813 (Box OS-35)
- Brant, Joseph (Captain), 1803; 1974.001 folder 4; 4602; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 10)
  1803 letter from Captain Joseph Brant, at Niagara, addressed "Dear Sir", re: consoling the addressee upon his recent removal from government office concerning "Indian Nations", mentions "Oghgwage Joseph" as bearer of the letter
- Brodhead, John Romeyn, 1846; 1974.009 folder 8; 4603; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 11)
  1846 letter, from John Romeyn Brodhead, at New York, to Alden J. Spooner, re: Brooklyn City Library honorary membership
- Brown, John, 1859; 1974.009 folder 9; 4604; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 12)
  1859 letter, from John Brown, in prison at Charlestown, VA, to Rev. Luther Humphrey, re: farewell.
- Burnet, William (Governor), 1722; 1974.009 folder 12; 4605; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 13)
  1722 military commission, appointing Francis Titus as Captain of Militia for Bushwick in Col. Van Brunt's Kings County Militia, signed by Governor William Burnet at Fort George, in New York
- Burr, Aaron, 1790, 1798, 1823, 1831, 1833; 1974.009 folder 13; 4606; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
  1790 letter from Aaron Burr, to Joseph Burroughs, at New Town, re: discharge of a debt owed to Mr. Mitchell, the late sheriff of Queens County; 1798 letter, from Aaron Burr, at Albany, to General Lamb, at New York, re: Albany news, mentions Edward Livingston, Ten Broeck, Denning, L'Hommedieu, White, Vail, and General Schuyler; 1823 letter, from Aaron Burr, at Albany, to John Greenwood, at New York, re: governmental appointments; 1831 cover note, signed by Aaron Burr, re: "opinion enclosed," with postscript, which mentions Mr. Jay and Mr. Burns; 1833 letter, from Aaron Burr, to B. F. Thompson, at New York, re: aid needed in removing a tenant from the Morrell house, mentions Judge Strong
- Butler, Benjamin Franklin, 1824, 1833; 1974.009 folder 14; 4607; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 15)
  1824 letter, from B. F. Butler (1795-1858), at Albany, to Messrs. Wells and Van Wagener, attorneys, at New York, re: papers in the care of Banker & Mabbutt; 1833 letter, from B. F .Butler, at Albany, to Victory Birdseye, at Pompey, Onondaga Co., NY, re: court cases
- Calhoun, John Caldwell, 1818, 1848; 1974.009 folder 15; 4711; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 16)
  1818 military pension claim, signed by Secretary of War John C. Calhoun, on behalf of Simeon Griswold of New York, for Revolutionary War service; 1848 note, from John C. Calhoun, enclosing payment for William Frederick Van Amringe's "An Investigation of the Theories of the Natural History of Man"
- Catlin, George, 1847; 1974.009 folder 17; 4608; 1 items (Box 1, Folder 17)
  1847 letter, From George Catlin, in France, to John Howard Payne, [at Paris?], re: requesting an interpreter, mentions a "M. de Cailleux" who is to inspect some of Catlin's designs intended for King Louis Philippe
- Champion, Epaphroditus, 1812; 1974.009 folder 18; 4609; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 18)
  1812 letter, from Epaphroditus Champion, at Washington, DC, to Timothy Green, at East Haddam, CT, re: a trade bill before the US House of Representatives authorizing the circumstances of importation of goods and merchandise from Great Britain
- Channing, William Ellery, 1833; 1974.009 folder 20; 4610; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 19)
  1833 letter, from William Ellery Channing, at Boston, to John Howard Payne, at New York, re: Channing's good wishes, but regret at his inability to further support Payne's work
- Choate, Rufus, 1841, 1844, 1849; 1974.009 folder 22; 4611; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 20)
  1841 letter, from Rufus Choate, at Boston, to Richard Salter Storrs Jr., at Andover, MA, re: suggested courses of study for Storrs's education; 1844 letter, from Rufus Choate, at Boston, to Richard Salter Storrs Jr., William T. Eustis, et al., as committee for a Society, at Boston, re: declining invitation to lecture before the Society; 1849 note, signed by Rufus Choate
- Clay, Henry, 1837; 1974.009 folder 23; 4612; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 21)
  1837 letter, from Henry Clay, at Washington, DC, to John Howard Payne, at New York, re: prospects for enacting copyright legislation
- Clinton, DeWitt, 1819; 1974.009 folder 24; 4613; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 22)
  1819 letter, from Governor DeWitt Clinton, at Albany, to Alden Spooner, re: judicial appointments, mentions Mr. Schenk, William Furman, Mr. Lefferts, Mr. Garrison
- Cornwallis, 1777; 1974.001 folder 5; 4614; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 23)
  1777 letter from Cornwallis to General George Washington, re: money and stores sent by General de H[eisler] for the Hessians taken prisoner at Trenton, and also requesting that a flag of truce be respected, thus allowing a surgeon, medicines, etc. to be delivered for the relief of wounded officers and men left at Princeton
- Curtis, George William, 1874, 1880; 1974.009 folder 27; 4619; 2 item (Box 1, Folder 24)
  1874 letter from George William Curtis, at Staten Island, to Dr. Richard Salter Storrs, re: declining invitations; 1880 letter, from Curtis, in Massachusetts, to Dr. Sanger, re: reform movement, mentions Dr. Henry Whitney Bellows, Charles Collins
- Dallas, George Mifflin, 1841; 1974.009 folder 29; 4620; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 25)
  1841 letter, from George Mifflin Dallas, at Philadelphia, to John L. O'Sullivan, at New York, re: suggesting that O'Sullivan "polish" Dallas's name
- Day, Thomas, 1784; 1974.009 folder 30; 4621; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 26)
  1784 letter, from Thomas Day, to Henry Laurens, at Charles Town, re: good wishes, and Laurens's family
- Elliott, Charles Loring, nd; 1974.009 folder 32; 4623; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 28)
  ND letter, from Charles Loring Elliott, at New York, to Gabriel Harrison, daguerreotypist [of Brooklyn], re: praising Harrison's work
- Emmet, B. [?], ND [c. 1820s-1830s]; 1974.009 folder 33; 4624; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 29)
  ND letter, from B. Emmet, to Alderman [John Yates] Cebra, at "Ferry Committee, Old Alms House" [NY], re: meeting, mentions "Mr. Whiting's resolution about the Leases of the Catharine and Fulton ferries"
- Enos, Roger (General), 1781; 1974.001 folder 6; 4615; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 30)
  1781 letter from General Roger Enos, at "Castelton," to Col. Ebenezer Walbridge, re: rendering approval of the Colonel's orders in a recent military action
- Everett, Alexander Hill, 1843; 1974.009 folder 34; 4625; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 31)
  1843 letter, from Alexander Hill Everett, at Boston, to John L. O'Sullivan, at New York, re: engraving of Everett, and Everett's straitened financial circumstances
- Evers, John, 1852; 1974.009 folder 36; 4626; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 32)
  1852 letter, from John Evers, at New York, to Gabriel Harrison, daguerreotypist [of Fulton Street, Brooklyn], re: praising Harrison's work
- Fish, Hamilton, 1868 (Box OS-35)
- Fox, George, ND; 1974.054; 4650; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Frémont, John Charles, 1888; 1974.010 folder 38; 4627; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 34)
  1888 letter, from John Charles Frémont, at Los Angeles, to Col. Charles Cyril Martin, Chief Engineer of the Brooklyn Bridge, re: projects at Redondo Beach and Inglewood, California
- Fulton, Robert, 1809; 1974.010 folder 40; 4628; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 35)
  1809 letter, from Robert Fulton, at Albany, to "Mr. Charles Brownne (sic), Ship Builder," at New York, re: work, exhorting Brownne to "use every exertion," and including an "order for $1,000
- Fulton, Robert, 1814; 1974.054; 4651; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Gallatin, Albert, 1803, 1813; 1974.010 folder 41; 4629; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 37)
  1803 letter, from United States Secretary of the Treasury Albert Gallatin, to Senator Christopher Ellery, re: Gallatin's intentions, viz. withdrawal of public monies from a certain bank, mentions "Mr. Foster;" 1813 letter from Gallatin to William Few, U. S. Commissioner of Loans, at New York, re: a transfer certificate of stock
- Garland, Hugh A., 1844; 1974.010 folder 42; 4630; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 38)
  1844 letter, from Hugh A. Garland, at Petersburg, VA, to Henry G. Langley, book seller at Astor House, New York, re: introducing "Mr. H. B. Gaines" as a customer
- Glover, John (General), 1780; 1974.001 folder 7; 4616; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 39)
  1780 letter from General Glover, at West Point, to "Mr. Fisher, A. [J.] Master, Fish Kill Landing," re: directing Fisher to supply the bearer, Major Leonard, with a horse
- Greene, Nathaniel (General), 1779; 1974.001 folder 8; 4617; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 40)
  1779 letter from General Nathaniel Greene to "Mr. Ming", re: instructions, ordering Ming to proceed to Fishkill, Danbury, and Reading, and to examine the camp equipage of regiments under the commands of General McDougal and General Putnam and then make a report
- Hancock, John, 1776; 1974.001 folder 9; 4618; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 41)
  1776 letter from John Hancock, President of the Continental Congress, at Philadelphia, to the Committee at Trenton, 22 January 1776, re: notice that a previous letter from the committee had been put before the Congress for consideration, and also requesting that the committee send a Brigadier General Prescott and a Captain Chace "who lately commanded the Gaspy arm'd vessel in Canada" to Philadelphia, the two being among a number of officers held prisoner at Trenton, lately escorted there by Colonel Wyncoop
- Hare, Francis, ND [c. 1776?]; 1974.010 folder 45; 4631; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 42)
  ND [c. 1776?] lengthy letter from Francis Hare, with seal, at "Herstmonceux" [Sussex], to John Laurens, at London, re: "the present crisis," discussing the situation of America, mentions "taxation" and "representation"
- Hoffman, Josiah Ogden, et al., 1812; 1974.010 folder 48; 4644; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 43)
  1812 letter, signed by Josiah Ogden Hoffman, T. L. Ogden, Samuel Boyd, and David Ogden, at New York City, to John Boyd, at Madrid, New York, as agent, re: a proposed turnpike to be built through lands owned by the signatories in St. Lawrence County, New York, a tax to be levied for the turnpike, proposed settlements in the county attendant on the turnpike's construction, and John Boyd's fitness as agent for the signatories
- Hughes, John Joseph (Bishop), 1843; 1974.010 folder 50; 4645; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 44)
  1843 letter, from New York Bishop John Joseph Hughes to Charles J. Harrison, at New York, re: decoration of churches, mentions St. Peter's Church, Jersey City
- Ingersoll, Charles Jared, 1843; 1974.010 folder 51; 4646; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 45)
  1843 letter, from Charles Jared Ingersoll, at Philadelphia, to the "Messrs. Langley," editors of the Democratic Review, at New York, re: two numbers of the Review not received
- Ingham, Charles C., ND; 1974.010 folder 52; 4647; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 46)
  ND letter, from the Irish portrait painter Charles C. Ingham (1796-1863), to the Brooklyn daguerreotypist Gabriel Harrison, re: Ingham's complimentary appraisal of Harrison's work
- Irving, Washington, 1841, 1857, ND; 1974.010 folder 53; 4648; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 47)
  1841 letter, from Washington Irving, at Sunnyside, Tarrytown, to Messrs. Langley, Booksellers, at Chatham, re: volumes of interest for research "about the present work"; 1857 letter from Irving, at Sunnyside, Tarrytown, to Alfred Jones Esq., re: Irving's thanks for receiving a copy of Jones's work, praising Jones, and warmly remembering Jones's father; ND letter, from Irving, at New York, to J. H. Payne Esq., at New York, re: a Mr. M'Lane, and a letter of introduction to "the American Minister at Mexico" [See also: letters of Washington Irving in "Henry Onderdonk Jr. (1804-1886) Correspondence, 1835-18—", Box A0028, folder "Irving, Washington"]
- Irving, Washington, 1830, nd; 1974.001 folder 11; 4632; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 48)
  3 letters, from Washington Irving to Henry Brevoort Jr.: Undated letter, re: a future meeting at West Point; 1830 letter, from Irving in London to Brevoort at Paris, expressing fatigue with London, wistfully recalling the "clear skies of Spain and the delicious climate of Andalusia," expressing fondness and intent to visit Paris and mentioning Iriving's brother, Peter Irving, and "that worthy Tar Jack Nicholson"; 1830 letter, also from Irving in London to Brevoort at Paris, re: a Mrs. Carson and her brother (at Cheltenham), and mentions travel of Irving's brother to Paris
- Jefferson, Thomas, 1803; 1974.054; 4652; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Johnson, Jeremiah, 1807; 1974.010 folder 54; 4649; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 50)
  1807 receipt for tax, signed by Jeremiah Johnson, "Collector of the Eighth Collection District," re: monies paid by Leffert Lefferts "for the heirs of Jacobus L. Lefferts"
- Johnson, Richard Mentor, 1834, 1842; 1974.010 folder 55; 4653; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 51)
  1834 letter from Richard Mentor Johnson, at Washington, D.C., to Charles P. Harrison, Esq., re: "Miniatures of the Illustrious Washington" and "suggestions upon a circulating medium"; 1842 letter, from Johnson to the Editors of the Democratic Review, re: subscription
- Johnson, William (Sir), 1770, (1865); 1974.010 folder 56; 4654; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 52)
  1770 order, from Sir William Johnson, addressed to Mayor Fonda, re: provisioning "this Cherokee Indian" with clothing and other items (with photocopy); (also, an 1865 letter from Lewis P. Clover, at Lanesborough, MA, to Alden J. Spooner, of the "Brooklyn Historical Society," presenting the Johnson letter to the Society)
- Kendall, Amos, 1843; 1974.010 folder 58; 4655; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 53)
  1843 letter, from Amos Kendall, at Washington, D.C., to Messrs. J. and Henry G. Langley, publishers of The United States Magazine & Democratic Review, at New York, re: arrangements for publication of Kendall's "Life of Jackson", mentions Mr. O'Sullivan
- King, Thomas Starr, [1859]; 1974.010 folder 59; 4656; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 54)
  [1859] signature of Thomas Starr King (fragment), attached to note: "Pinned to letter of Nathaniel B. Borden to Rev. Caleb D. Bradlee, Dec. 6, 1859"
- Knox, Henry (Gen.), 1780; 1974.010 folder 60; 4657; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 55)
  1780 wartime letter, from Revolutionary War General Henry Knox, at Camp Precaness (Preakness), New Jersey, to Colonel Joseph Ward, at Boston, re: Knox's indignation at the poor state of the army, extensively expressed, and concern for the intention of the British to attack the French troops at Rhode Island
- L'Hommedieu, Ezra, 1782, (1878); 1974.010 folder 66; 4658; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 56)
  1782 wartime letter, from Ezra L'Hommedieu, at Middletown, to Nathaniel Shaw Esq., re: a proposal for a prisoner exchange, requesting the release of a Captain Seth Overton, seized at Sag Harbor and held at New York, to be exchanged for "Brooks," taken at Fishers Island and held at New London; (1878 Long Island Historical Society order slip, printed matter, signed on reverse by James H. L'Hommedieu of Brooklyn
- Lamar, Mirabeau Buonaparte, 1857; 1974.010 folder 62; 4659; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 57)
  1857 letter, from Mirabeau Buonaparte Lamar [M. B. Lamar], to Mr. Savage [at New York], re: editing of Lamar's work, mentions sailing from New York [for Central America] and the Saint Nicholas Hotel
- Lee, Charles (General), 1780; 1974.001 folder 13; 4633; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 58)
  1780 letter from General Charles Lee, at Baltimore, addressed "My Dear Sir—," re: advance of funds, drawn upon the addressee, made by Lee on behalf of William Goddard and Eleazer Oswald, mentions Sir Charles Davis and Sir Charles Banbury
- Lee, Robert E., 1841, 1842; 1974.010 folder 63; 4660; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 59)
  2 receipts, 1841 and 1842, printed matter, and an 1841accounting of expenses, signed by Captain Robert E. Lee, of the Corps of Engineers, for Fort Hamilton, NY
- Lepsius, Karl Richard, 1881; 1974.010 folder 64; 4661; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 60)
  3 letters, in German, dated 1881, from the Egyptologist Karl Richard Lepsius, at Berlin (one with "Königliche Bibliothek" letterhead), to an unidentified gentleman [poss. in New York], re: subscription to "Aegyptischen Denkmälerwerks", with catalog of antiquarian and anthropological materials
- Lewis, Zechariah, 1832; 1974.010 folder 65; 4662; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 61)
  1832 letter, from Zechariah Lewis, at Brooklyn, to Col. Alden Spooner, re: wine cultivation and the "Isabella Grape", includes an 1832 circular, printed matter, authored by Spooner (attached)
- Lincoln, Abraham, 1865; 1974.076 folder 1; 4663; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Commission from War Department
- Lincoln, Abraham, 1862; 1974.076 folder 2; 4664; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Memorandum
- Lincoln, Benjamin (General), 1779; 1974.001 folder 15; 4634; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 64)
  1779 letter from General Benjamin Lincoln, at "Head Quarters near Stone Ferry," to Colonel Henry B. Livingston, at Rhinebeck, NY, re: commending Livingston's past conduct and wishing him safe return from imminent travel abroad
- Louis XV, King of France, [1730?], 1755; 1974.010 folder 67; 4665; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 65)
  [1730?] official document, signed by Louis XV, King of France, re: land in the town of Blois, also signed by Phelypeaux; 1755 official document, signed by Louis XV, re: land, mentions the church at Blois, also signed by Bouillé
- Madison, James, 1812 (Box OS-35)
- Marble, Manton, 1860; 1974.010 folder 70; 4666; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 66)
  1860 letter, from Manton Marble, at "World Office," to S. Hastings Grant Esq., Librarian of the Mercantile Library Association, re: collection of "those papers" from Grant, and delivery of "the daily" to Grant
- Marcy, William Learned (Gov.), 1833; 1974.010 folder 71; 4667; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 67)
  1833 letter from New York Governor William Learned Marcy, at Albany, to John Howard Payne, at New York, re: authorising Payne to include Marcy's name in Payne's "proposed work"
- Marston, John*, 1713; 1974.010 folder 72; 4668; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 68)
  1713 land deed, from John Marston [*alternatively spelled John Marstin, and John Martins], to Nicholas Haight, both of Flushing, Queens, LI, for land at Flushing
- McKenney, Thomas Loraine, 1846; 1974.010 folder 68; 4669; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 69)
  [Indian interest] 1846 letter, from Thomas Loraine McKenney, at Lyceum House, Brooklyn, to Rev. Mr. Harley, re: McKenney's book, and appealing to Rev. Harley to help promote "the preservation, & future well-being of the remnants of the Aboriginal race"
- Mitchell, Samuel L. (Dr.), 1811; 1974.010 folder 73; 4670; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 70)
  1811 letter, from Dr. Samuel L. Mitchell, at New York, to Dr. Benjamin Franklin Thompson, at Setauket, LI, re: thanking Thompson for his oration to "the Columbian Order," and mentioning Mitchell's own talk "on the life, exploits, and precepts of Tammany," the letter composed on a circular of the "University of the State of New York College of Physicians and Surgeons" (printed matter)
- Moulton, Joseph White, 1846; 1974.010 folder 76; 4671; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 71)
  1846 letter, from Joseph White Moulton, at New York City, to Edmund Bailey O'Callaghan, re: reply to O'Callaghan's queries, researching the history of Novum Belgium, mentions indian treaties, land patents, Col. Brant, Spofford, De Vries, the West India Company
- Napier, Charles (Sir), 1858; 1974.010 folder 77; 4672; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 72)
  1858 letter, from Sir Charles Napier, of Her Britannic Majesty's Legation at Washington, DC, to Captain Sands of the U.S.S. Susquehanna, re: the British government's appreciation of Sands's role in the first attempts to lay the Transatlantic cable
- Newman, Francis William, 1870; 1974.010 folder 78; 4673; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 73)
  1870 letter, from Francis William Newman, at Keswick, to "My Dear Nicholson," re: discussing the Franco-Prussian War
- Nicholls, Richard, 1665 (Box OS-35)
- Paulding, James Kirke, ND [1839?], 1839; 1974.011 folder 79; 4674; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 74)